It is very important for every family to have a health insurance in today's time.
Illness of any member of the family can wipe out your entire savings.
Hi friend,
today we will talk about health insurance
which has a cover of Rs 5 lakh. For this
part, we will discuss some technical tips
for Sachin in this video
and for those technical tips,
we will compare the four companies which we have selected among themselves. Their
technical terms are
plain settlement ratio, room rent limit up
to 99 stories, job and no claim bonus, no
cashless hospital,
cooperative fertilizer sector and
hospitalization at home, ambulance charges, existence in less,
maternity cover, free
health check-up, discount and renewal,
free hospitalization cover.
We will discuss 24 companies in this,
first is Star Health,
second is Aditya Birla Capital, third is Time
HQ and fourth is our government company New
India Assurance. Let
us first talk about the technical terms,
claim settlement ratio, what
is plain settlement ratio, suppose any
insurance company  Hand cases come to the company
and they pay 97% of the cases, the
remaining three either reject it or
put it in pending. In this way,
this Sarvan shampoo send of that company, we are doing
four company computers, their
CSR is of Star Health, 90% is
cent on Aditya Laine's phone, IS June
or 70% is cent,
next time there is room rent limit, it
covers differently in different conditions
and some policies provide common room cover,
some policies provide private room,
some mantra Om is displayed in the ward
and in private room,
a separate strip is given to the patient,
in this total single private AC room is
provided, Aditya Birla Group provides 4
single private AC rooms, that is seen that every
one India, any room whose
value is Rs 5,000, next by
dividing the coverage, please, in today's time
all health insurance policies
provide visit coverage, in this there are some plants, some
time period, after that if
a person becomes a
patient  If the insurance is very thin
then companies provide coverage. Let me
explain it to you in brief about the Restriction of Cover Restoration of Power G.
In a family there are five members,
husband, wife and their three children ABCD.
Suppose one of them falls ill and
incurs an expense of ₹5000 due to illness,
which is covered by the insurance policy.
Now during that year if C falls
ill and has a
disease due to meeting C, then in that case there will be no restoration.
Again that approved member will
not get registration. If the balance is different
then the second C will also get a cover of ₹5000.
In these four companies,
Star Health has a cover once in a year, Tata Insurance once in a year,
Tata Capital once in a year
and New India Insurance will
get a restoration cover of ₹5 lakh only in this.
Next9 Cream Bonus Stitch Example:
What is No Claim Bonus?
Suppose Star Health is a company and it has given a No Claim
Bonus of ₹2.5 lakh at the year end up to a
maximum of ₹10 lakh.  Five lines, you
know that if you did not pay any premium in the first year, then
your cover was 5 lakhs,
2.5 lakhs will be added to it and for the
next year you will have to do it again
and send this message for only 5 lakhs,
please
a second year b if you do not take it for this reason then
your cover will be 1.5 lakhs, you
Lakshmi you points you like
and generally it will be 10 lakh rupees and you will have to
decide the premium accordingly if you do
not take it for the third year then your
cover will be 10 lakhs only because it is
written in the policy that it is 2.5 lakh rupees every year
and maximum 5 lakh rupees, so you should add ₹5 in
advance, then definitely
your cover will be 10 lakhs
and the premium you will pay will be 5 lakhs
accordingly,
in this case the premium will be decided according to
2.5 lakhs per year for additional 5 lakhs, when
2.5 lakhs per year and addition up to 5 lakhs, better
exhibition and new insurance
1.25 lakhs per year and  2.5 lakhs
are additional cashless hospitals.
Whenever you take this insurance policy,
you should know about such conditions. The
current insurance policies
provide cashless facility. Meaning, if a
patient gets hospitalized, after that whatever
expenses he incurs,
whatever money he incurs, the insurance company and the
hospital settle it among themselves. It is
cashless, in this the patient does not have to do anything.
So according to that, Char Help has
11000 plus cashless hospitals, 42
in Gurgaon. Tata Birla Capital has 85
surplus hospitals, 105 in Gurgaon.
Tata Magic Bus has 75 surplus hospitals
active in Gurgaon and New India has
2000 plus cashless hospitals, of
which twenty four are in Gurgaon. Voice
mail village. Who am I talking to? Then I
am a village resident and I have friends
who wanted a health insurance policy,
so they were asking me for some guidelines,
so I thought let's make a video, in this
I will now see what happens in the village.  There are
hospitals in Star Halki which are 42 hospitals, these are Columbia,
Columbia Asia
Hospital, Max Hospital, Medanta Hospital,
Park Hospital, Aryan Hospital,
Rock Land Hospital, Shivam Hospital, there is a
long list, you can pause it and see it,
next is Aditya Birla ji, there are
85 surplus hospitals, there are 105 in the video, there are
34 in Din, I know there is Max,
Centre for Sight, Mamta Hospital,
Sanjivani Hospital, there is only Front Hospital,
Vatika Hospital
and there are multi-speciality hospitals,
you can punch it in the computer and
see the video, next these 75
surplus hospitals, what is in Sirgaon, there are
346 Medanta,
Dhakad Hospital, Adventure Hospital,
Pushpanjali Hospital, similarly
in New India Assurance, out of 24 Gurus, 24
June is in Gurgaon and it is normal, it is good
and is
nearest to all the places, in which there is Max
Hospital, Medanta, Artemis from Paras,
Columbia Asia, 34,
Tirth Ram Hospital, Neelkanth Hospital,
we are hospitals, along with this, there is good, there is
also shortage in India
Okay, next is copper
coins, let's understand the example, suppose
a patient has to pay Rs 1 lakh
hospitalization tax in the hospital, then if there is
top twenty percent in that policy, then the
patient will have to pay pizza and the
company will pay 80 thousand, the insurance company will
settle the
case on my channel, in that
police claim brother insurance company Tata
AIG Aditya Birla Group and New India
Fully are
plane brother insurance companies,
next refer to hospitalization
principal addition, what is it, suppose there is
a patient and he is sick, then he is
taking medicines etc. as per some small planning, getting
checkups done and if
he does this routine for some time, then he takes
medicines as per some planning
and gets checkups done, but after some time
he has to undergo treatment, then during
this time, even before the hospitalization,
whatever expenses the patient has, be
it any medical test or
medicine, that is also covered nowadays,
insurance companies are giving that
in this case, there are four help varieties for seven days, but for the
seven days Tata Aditya
Birla is providing seven days  Till New India 30s
hospitalization is that
if a patient is hospitalized and there is a
good recovery in his illness and
he is discharged,
even after discharge, a lot of expenses remain
pending like
after recharge the cost of routine checkup, medicine
cost, in that case also companies are
giving relief cover in which Tata AIG for up to 90 days,
Aditya Birla Group for 90 days, Tata for 90 days or
those who have judicial students,
next hospitalization at home, now if there is any
pending case in that time, if any
hospital is conducting research here and it does
not have beds, then the hospital suggests you
that you have to pay a full fee, we will subscribe to it, in
that
case also, there is cover in the coaching that is going on nowadays, on that
Star Health is giving
cover up to 5 lakhs, whoever comes to us, he has got a
complete cover of 5 lakhs, its size is Star, in
Fertilization at Home, Aditya
Birla Group also 5 lakhs, Tata also 5 lakhs and
New India is giving it, I do
not pay any money in In India hospitalization
Next ambulance for
two-four days. Now what happens is that some percent of the
people, considering their illness to be minor, go for
treatment in some small Clarify clinic.
That small
doctor with a link tells them that you
need to be treated in a big hospital and
you will have to go by ambulance only.
In that case, insurance companies
also provide you ambulance cover, in
which Star Health, which will be your express, will provide
Aditya Birla Group Exact
Place, Tata Sky TV will provide coverage up to Rs. 3000, Undhya will provide coverage up to Rs.
5000 in a year.
Next, cover exists in English. There are
some diseases for
which you cannot avail cover immediately after taking the policy. There are
some time periods for it. Different diseases are covered at
different times. Among them,
brain and they include asthma,
diabetes, high BP, thyroid, liver,
birds, OPD for animals, cancer etc. There are many more.
In case of these diseases, your Saral cover will provide
your body cover after three years of Tata Easy
policy, after three years of
Grandmother Birla policy, after three years of New India policy,
after four years of
Maternity cover.
You will ask
these companies' policies which we are
talking about.  I am just asking which one
provides maternity cover.
In this, there is Star Health which gives 15000
in normal and 20,000 in serial. It is
called education and it gives you maternity cover.
Rest Aditya Birla, Tata AIG, New
India is not giving maternity cover. Its
name is
hands free health checkup.
Suppose if you have taken a policy
and you have done it in the same way and
you have
not made any claim, then Star Help will give
you a free checkup once a year.
Aditya Birla Group will give you a free health check-up once in a year. Tata
AIG will give you a free health check-up in 2 years. If you do not do this, then
New India Assurance does
not provide you the facility of free health checkup.
A doctor has said that the price of the policy is different at different times.
I am talking about the present situation. Star Health is
giving a discount of Tencent in renewal.
Aditya Birla Capital,
Tata AIG, Nidhi is
not giving any renewal discount at present.  That you should
start paying this bramble in the coming time, the
Neck Safe premium,
you can decide for yourself by looking at the value of the premium and also by looking at it,
which policy will be better for you,
Star Help, you can
see on the left side, 1672 performance, this is
for family, in the family like there is husband, wife
and two children, that which
you
can see in the light of your brightness screen, six ₹90, this is for single person,
if a single person is taking his health
insurance, then in Aditya Birla
Group, there is Pawan for family at 1662
and for single there is Sona Unnati pork,
for Tata AIG,
according to Tata, this is Rs. 95 for family,
Rs. 662 for single and our
New India Government Company, Rs. 1259 per month
for family, Rs. 56001 per month for the
individual, I have covered almost all the
technical terms and basic transfers
in this video, you
can go with any one of these four companies, you
can buy any one of the nourished and
In today's time, it is
very important for you to take a health insurance policy.
Jai Hind Jai Bharat.